# Balasubramanian

12 Charing cross, London WC2H OHR bala.sekar@outlook.com
(+44) 07404729011

## Summary

Cross functional developer with 7 years' experience in software and web development. I have worked as a full stack developer along with test automation and deployment (docker, Jenkins, AWS). I have also participated in many hackathons conducted in my office and have given solutions to some problems. I have experience of working in Agile methodologies. Interested in solving any business problem using latest technology and programming standards.

#### Skills

**Languages** Java, Nodejs

**Frameworks** Dropwizard, Spring, Jersey, Junit, Mockito, Sinon-Stub, Selenium, Express, React-Redux,

hibernate, JDBI

Query Language Graphql

Language

**Database** Postgres, MySQL

**Deployment** Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Pipeline as Code, Ansible

**Architecture** Microservice, Event Driven architecture, REST based APIs

## Work Experience

2015 - Present Cross Functional Developer

Connected Homes-London, UK

2014 - 2015 Application Developer

Cognizant Technology Solutions Ltd

2010 - 2014 Application Developer

Infosys Technologies Ltd

#### Education

2006 - 2010 Bachelor of Engineering

Anna University - Chennai, India

## Hackathon Ideas

**Support Tools** Web App to display British Gas customer details to the support team by just

providing the account number (Nodejs)

**Report Monitor** Web App to display the Report of some statistics requested by the Product manager

(Dropwizard)

**Energy Cost Predictor** App to predict the energy cost that customer might get for any given day in the

future using polynomial regression (Machine Learning)

**Data Generator** Node App to generate test SQL data files for a list of tables and list of users which

are configurable and the user data is anonymized (Nodejs)

### Professional courses

2017

**AWS** Developer